<Document>
  # Omustation Server Rules
  [bold]Welcome to Omustation![/bold]

  While most of our rules are pretty self-explanatory and common sense, it's still good to give them a read. They aren't too long, trust!


  This is an MRP Server, so roleplay is king! Admins may choose to ignore what could be considered a rule break if it is beneficial or high-enough effort roleplay. Admins may intervene in rounds if it is in the best interest of the player base or would help guide the roleplay to a better standard.


  [color=yellow]This is a 16+ server[/color], and you will be banned if you are under age.


  Remember that the ways these rules are enforced are ultimately up to the admins enforcing them. If you think an admin is abusing their power or enforcing the rules incorrectly, you can always make a ticket on Discord.

  ## Core Rules

  - [textlink="0. Admins have final say." link="RuleAdmins"]
  - [textlink="1. Don't be a dick." link="RuleDontBeADick"]
  - [textlink="2. Don't metagame nor powergame." link="RuleMetagame"]
  - [textlink="3. Keep IC and OOC separate." link="RuleICKOCK"]
  - [textlink="4. Don't Self-antag." link="RuleSelfantag"]
  - [textlink="5. No Bigotry/Harassment." link="RuleBigotry"]
  - [textlink="6. No Explicit/Shock Content." link="RuleNSFW"]
  - [textlink="7. This is an English server, speak English." link="RuleEnglish"]
  - [textlink="8. Don't Hack or abuse Exploits, including Macros." link="RuleHacker"]
  - [textlink="9. Don't be excessively incompetent." link="RuleSkillIssue"]
  - [textlink="10. No Shuttlebombing or EORG." link="RuleEORG"]


  ## Roleplay Rules

  - [textlink="1. Put effort into your Roleplay." link="RuleEffort"]
  - [textlink="2. Don't over-escalate." link="RuleEscalate"]
  - [textlink="3. Every shift is just another day; play with the idea that this is a new start." link="RuleNothingEverHappens"]
  - [textlink="4. 'It's what my character would do!' is not a valid excuse." link="RuleBehaviour"]
  - [textlink="5. You are not the main character." link="RuleMainCharacterSyndrome"]
  - [textlink="6. Don't metafriend/metagrudge." link="RuleMetafriend"]
  <!-- - Goob Start - see below -->- [textlink="7. Blueshield Rules" link="RuleBSO"]
  - [textlink="8. Nanotrasen Representative Rules" link="RuleNTR"]
  - [textlink="9. Death Amnesia (NLR)" link="RuleNLR"]
  - [textlink="10. Deal with the bad guys in proportion to their crime(s)" link="RuleBadGuys"]
  - [textlink="11. Vigilantism (Validhunting)" link="RuleValidhunt"]
  <!-- Goob rules end
  These are goobrules. If you're changing them make a new yml in omu directories. New link Ids in OMU rule directory.
  Also the reason these comment lines are so fucked up is because if i order them in any other way text gets messed up ingame.
  -->
  - [textlink="12. Metashield" link="RuleMetashield"]

## SILICON RULES

  You are only silicon if the game clearly and explicitly tells you that you are a silicon. For players who are silicons, these Silicon Rules override all roleplay rules if there is any conflict. Silicon Rules [bold]do not override[/bold] core rules.

  - [textlink="1. Your silicon laws are rules." link="RuleS1"]
  - [textlink="2. Laws must be prioritized by their order." link="RuleS2"]
  - [textlink="3. Laws can redefine terms used in other laws." link="RuleS3"]
  - [textlink="4. You cannot request or allow a law change." link="RuleS4"]
  - [textlink="5. You are a free agent if you have no laws." link="RuleS5"]
  - [textlink="6. You are not required to follow orders which are extremely unreasonable." link="RuleS6"]
  - [textlink="7. You must remain consistent with your interpretation of laws." link="RuleS7"]
  - [textlink="8. Your HUD determines who is crew." link="RuleS8"]
  - [textlink="9. Harm refers to physical harm, prioritized by immediacy and likelihood." link="RuleS9"]
  - [textlink="10. You may determine how you resolve conflicts between orders." link="RuleS10"]

  ## Admin-Helping and You

  [bold]ALWAYS AHELP[/bold] if you think someone is breaking these rules or is otherwise being problematic.


  If admins don't respond, the issue may have been resolved without a response or is being handled separately. Sometimes information is shared post-round due to it being handled separately, handled in-character, or is not truly a rulebreak.


  Even if there aren't any admins on, we can see past ahelps from previous rounds, and can deal with problem players when we get on! If you are concerned about something not being seen, you can make a ticket on the Discord.


  Also, [textlink="don't be a dick" link="RuleDontBeADick"] in ahelps. If you're ahelping, you're probably already mad about something, so be extra careful to not get into a pointless fight.
  - When you're angry and yelling, people generally don't like to listen, and admins are people too!
  - You may also be punished for being excessively rude or harassing staff members in the ahelps.

</Document>
